Tim Hordern

611 Grand St, Apt 2B

Brooklyn, NY 11211-3573

Summary

Professional Agile QA Engineer with detailed experience across large system implementations in complex environments. Deeply passionate about product quality, fast automated testing, using testing for fast feedback, team and process improvement, agile, and building real products that delight customers.

Experience with Cucumber, Selenium, Capybara, CasperJS, Cucumber.js, Gatling, Ruby, Rails, Scala, iOS and Android testing, Frank, GitHub, Continuous Integration toolsets (Jenkins, TeamCity), Amazon Web Services (AWS), Heroku and other tools.

Professional Experience (Summary)

- Agile QA Engineer Intent Media (2013 to Now)
- Senior Consultant ThoughtWorks (2011 to 2013)
- Technical Test Lead Infosys (2010)
- Consultant Accenture (2006 to 2009)
- Analyst General Motors (2003 to 2005)

Professional Experience (Detail)

Intent Media 2013 to Now

Agile QA Engineer

- Functional tester across full technical stack, including front-end JavaScript (for desktop, responsive and mobile views), backend applications in Java, Rails, database and storage testing (MySQL, Vertica, S3, MongoDB), API and iOS SDK testing, Node.js applications.
- Developed automated tests in mocha and Cucumber.js for Node.js applications. Built a service testing harness in Gatling, a Scala tool, for functional/performance testing.
- Improved QA team practices to help team scale and reduce errors and refreshed QA recruiting process.
- Expanded monitoring dashboard ad placement scraping in CasperJS, and automated tests for early warning of production issues using RSpec & CasperJS. Expanded and scripted release notes tool.

ThoughtWorks 2011 to 2013

Senior Consultant

Experience Designer (XD)

April 2013 to May 2013

Government Rail Organisation

- Designer for organisation-wide iOS application for rail network management. Ran user testing of iOS applications with range of users, including in-situ user testing sessions (onboard train).
- Designed wireframes and prototypes for iOS applications. Developed assets in Adobe Illustrator.

Quality Analyst (QA) March 2013

Not-for-Profit Organisation

Functional tester for Android tablet application. Performance tested Rails backend on Heroku.

Developer/Quality Analyst (QA)

January 2013

Consumer Law Firm

• Front End Developer, rapidly built pages in Node.js/CoffeeScript/Jade stack. Designed wireframes and UI components for prototype mockups.

Quality Analyst (QA)

October 2012 to January 2013

Global Charity Organisation

- Tester for Customer Portal and Web Services, incorporating exploratory testing and automated test development in Selenium. Built Gatling test suite in Scala for SOAP services, microservices (HTTP/JSON) and HTML5 front-end. Helped team optimise workflows, Kanban boards and metrics.
- Developed Atlassian Bamboo CI build light and build monitor information radiators.
- Worked with GitHub support team to restore core repository after production corruption.

Tim Hordern

Telephone: +1 (443) 839-3635 Email: tim.hordern@gmail.com

Product Manager (PM) / Business Analyst (BA)

November 2012

Global Charity Organisation

 Scoped & managed user stories with acceptance criteria in Atlassian JIRA. Analysed integration systems for future development work.

Agile Consultant August 2012

Supermarket and Retail Chain

Consultant for agile and DevOps fast-track assessment. Conducted project analysis and inception
planning for proposed fast-track project. Agile coaching of project team lead. Developed Kanban
walls for pilot agile teams.

Quality Analyst (QA)

November 2011 to July 2012

Not-For-Profit Organisation

- Tester for iOS application and .NET webservice, incorporating exploratory testing, accessibility testing, field handset testing and automated test development in Frank.
- Built and managed TestFlight instance for iOS beta deployment to 100+ internal and external beta users. Managed Jenkins CI instance and build pipeline. Developed build monitor dashboard and build lights for monitoring Jenkins builds.
- · Built visual design wall to elicit feedback from organisation in a cohesive product view.
- Provided guidance on iTunes App Store submissions, management and marketing.
- Tester for .NET web application, incorporating exploratory testing and automated testing development in Selenium.

Quality Analyst (QA)

August 2011 to November 2011

Global Online Real Estate Advertising

• Tester for Java/Ruby web application. Developed Cucumber acceptance tests for legacy product and training Java developers in adding tests.

Quality Analyst (QA)

February 2011 to June 2011

Advertising and Directory Listing

 Tester for Ruby big data analytics and reporting platform, incorporating exploratory testing, debugging & developing fixes for encoding issues, automated test development and client report testing. Developed cross-team automated integration tests.

Infosys 2010

Test Manager

Test Manager for SAP SRM Upgrade project managing offshore testing team.

Accenture 2006 to 2009

Consultant

Project Management Consultant

2008

• Established and coordinated project management office (PMO), planned future project phase resourcing & activities for transformation.

Conversions Team Lead 2007 to 2008

 Planned and delivered data migration effort for large SAP PM/MM upgrade. Managed team of developers, analysts and client SMEs. Developed test strategy documents and conversions plan for SAP MM/PM upgrade.

Test Analyst 2006 to 2007

 Test Analyst for Oracle (Retek) Retail Price Management (RPM) implementation and in-store & POS retail systems.

General Motors 2003 to 2005

Analyst

SAP Analyst 2004 to 2005

Reporting/System Analyst for SAP R/3 AP, invoicing and Procure-To-Pay processes.

Electronic Catalogue Administrator

2004 to 2005

• SAP SRM Administrator, developed and managed data in Requisite electronic catalogues, in conjunction with external vendors.

Tim Hordern

Telephone: +1 (443) 839-3635 Email: tim.hordern@gmail.com

Reporting and Database Analyst

2004

Reporting and Database Analyst for Procurement department, with direct executive and CEO reporting. Developed and administered reporting toolsets and redeveloped key database to streamline end of month reconciliation.

Conversions (Data Migration) Analyst

2003 to 2004

Delivered data migration and go-live capability for large SAP MM/SRM implementation. Led Conversions team across multiple rollouts and managed Data Cleansing team.

Supplier Enablement Analyst

2003 to 2004

System Analyst for SAP SRM & Requisite electronic catalogues implementation.

Education

University of Melbourne, Australia - Bachelor of Information Systems Victorian Certificate of Education (VCE) – ENTER 98.75 (Top 2%)

2005

1995 to 2000

Skills Overview

Primary Experience:

- Cucumber Experienced
- Selenium Experienced
- Capybara Experienced CasperJS Intermediate
- Sauce Labs/BrowserStack Intermediate
- Gatling Experienced
- Ruby/Rails Experienced Tester, Intermediate Developer
- Node.JS Intermediate
- Cucumber.is Experienced
- Clojure Beginner
- Scala Intermediate
- Objective-C Intermediate
- iOS Deployment Intermediate
- iOS Automated Testing (particularly Frank, exposure to Kiwi & KIF) - Intermediate
- Scripting (Bash, PowerShell, etc) -Intermediate

Data Toolset:

- Vertica Intermediate
- MySQL Intermediate
- MongoDB Intermediate
- Hadoop Beginner

Development Infrastructure:

- Jenkins CI Experienced
- TeamCity CI Intermediate
- Puppet Intermediate
- Ansible Beginner

Creative Toolset:

- Adobe Photoshop Beginner
- Adobe Illustrator Beginner
- Balsamiq Mockups Intermediate

Additional Technologies:

- Cloud deployment on AWS, Heroku Intermediate
- Cloud instance management on AWS and RightScale Intermediate
- GitHub & Git Intermediate
- SAP R/3 4.6C to ECC 6.0: LSMW, PLM, MM, PM, SRM, MDM, Requisite, Basis, including Configuration; User and Profile Management, Audit and Compliance; and Development Migration/Transport Management (Rev-Trac) - Experienced
- Oracle Retail RPM, RMS, RDF Experienced
- Atlassian JIRA & Confluence Experienced
- Pivotal Tracker Experienced
- HP Quality Center (QC) TestDirector and WinRunner Experienced
- Remedy Service Desk Intermediate
- C#.NET Experienced Tester, Intermediate Developer
- SpecFlow Experienced
- NUnit Intermediate